Susanne Morganstein

Grants Administrator / IRB Administrator / Accounting

Holmes, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Susanne-Morganstein/96b1472d5c0313d9

Grants Administrator with over 10 years of progressive experience in pre- and post-award research grants management. Past positions provide a background in payroll, purchasing and customer service. Quick learner with excellent analytical, problem solving, computer and communication skills. Team player with ability to work independently.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Grants Administrator / IRB Administrator / Accounting

POLISHER RESEARCH INSTITUTE - August 2008 to January 2016

- and post award grants management for two departments (Research and Counseling for Caregivers) with yearly budgets ranging from \$600,000 to \$1.3 million
- Prepared and submitted new grant applications per application specifications: create budgets, charts and tables; format documents; complete all forms necessary for submission; and upload to funding agencies.
- Submitted all progress reports, financial reports and grant closing reports in timely fashion.
- Ensured compliance of all grants per OMB Circulars A-110 and A-122.
- Created schedules and provide documentation required for A-133 single audits.
- Updated all government sites to maintain active status for federal grants.

Managed project accounting infrastructure

- Reconciled general ledger accounts on a monthly basis based on fiscal year and grant year; created journal entries and entered using Microsoft Dynamics software.
- Created fiscal year budgets for both departments.
- Managed all financial transactions (check requests, travel reimbursement, credit card reconciliation, and invoice payments) to ensure that they are charged appropriately to grants and maintain records for audit purposes.
- Accurate and timely billing of contracts.
- Completed federal cash draws for NIH grant.
- Forecasted revenues and expenditures with Principal Investigators to effectively plan projects and avoid cost overruns.

Facilitated other departmental activities

- Entered Payroll using Time Trak software.
- Coordinated the sale of Research Department's library, the move of Research Department to main building, and responsible for finding an additional site for the sleep study to conduct its overnight stays for participants. Served as Institutional Review Board (IRB) Administrator
- Confirmed all protocols meet HHS Regulations for the Protection of Human Subjects in Research (45CFR46).
- Reviewed all IRB applications and amendments for completeness and make initial assessment for type of review.
- Arranged all meetings: set agendas, confirm quorum, and record minutes.
- Ensured all assurances are up to date with OHRP.

POLISHER RESEARCH INSTITUTE - North Wales, PA - 2008 to 2016

Purchasing Agent

POINT OF PURCHASE - Philadelphia, PA - 2001 to 2002

Purchasing Agent

CHARMING SHOPPES, INC - Bensalem, PA - 2000 to 2001

New Store Opening Manager

DAVID'S BRIDAL - Conshohocken, PA - 1999 to 2000

Purchasing Agent

DAVID'S BRIDAL - Conshohocken, PA - 1995 to 1999

Computer Background

• Proficient in the following software: Microsoft Office 2013 (Excel, Word, Outlook, PowerPoint, Access); Great Plains Dynamics; Time Trak Payroll System

EDUCATION

Masters of Science in Hospitality Management

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - Rochester, NY August 1994

SKILLS

Excel (10+ years), Word (10+ years), Great Plains (7 years), Powerpoint (7 years), Access (9 years), Pivot Tables (5 years)